VINCENT R. TAIJERON

6/3 Shevchenko Ave Odesa, Ukraine

Mobile: +38 067 371 4805

Email: vincent.taijeron@gmail.com

Web: www.taijeronv.info

I am a competent and reliable professional with 15+ years of experience training and educating cadets, soldiers, officers, and non-commissioned officers. Proven ability to operate effectively in stressful environments. Recognized by my colleagues for my integrity and professionalism.

## **EXPERIENCE**

International Monitoring Officer, PAE, September 2014 – Present

- Standardized team patrols by applying military planning methods improving the team's coordination and efficiency during operations.
- Planned and supervised the execution of four "2nd of May" patrols, ensuring the team's safety.
- Effectively managed a team of 21 individual personalities ensuring a peaceful work environment.
- Monitored over 400 kilometers of the Transnistrian border, providing the OSCE with accurate information regarding the security situation.

Senior Curriculum Developer, Odesa Land Forces Academy, Odesa Ukraine August 2013 - September 2014

- Advised Major General Gulayk on the best way to integrate our NATO program into the 2015 academic year curriculum.
- Designed and taught a program of instruction to 2nd, 3rd, and 4th-year cadets, furthering their understanding of NATO operations.
- Taught the cadets how to improve their tactical-decision making using the "Follow Me" program.
- Developed a block of instruction featuring NATO mechanized infantry and armor operations for 35 students attending the Captain's Advanced Course, giving them an in-depth understanding.

Embedded Police Mentor, DynCorp International, Khowst Province, Afghanistan June 2011 - August 2013

- Mentored a special unit of 10 Afghan patrolmen tasked with augmenting coalition forces and securing FOB Salerno.
- Developed and taught a one-week induction program to my ten-man police unit, improving their ability to operate with coalition forces.
- Assisted 33 patrolmen in planning independent night patrols.
- Participated in over 50 mounted and dismounted combat patrols with the US Army while advising the Afghan police.

USMA Deputy Head of The Simulation Center, United States Military Academy, West Point, NY Aug 2004-Jun 2011

- Enhanced the Military Science 3 and 4 programs by integrating the "Follow Me" program which was used to practice making tactical decisions.
- Incorporated the Follow Me simulation into three military science courses, one college major (Defense Strategic Studies), and two leadership courses for the department of Behavioral Science and Leadership.
- Assisted instructor's in using the "Follow Me" program to achieve class learning outcomes in decision-making.
- Integrated Virtual Battlespace 2 into cadet basic training, providing over 1000 cadets an opportunity to practice squad fire and movement techniques before going to the field.
- Increased the use of the Simulation Center by 100%.

## **KEY SKILLS**

Briefings and Presentations Computer Technology and Networking Military Education and Training Operations Planning Written Reports and Assessments

## **EDUCATION**

Guam Community College, Technical Electronics, 1981 Central Texas College, General Studies, 1989